Guide to the William H. Johnson Papers
William H. Johnson Papers
- Tobacco Committees, Consulting, Reports, and Related Files, 1962-1984; 1962 1984; 3.5 linear feet
  - "Recommendations for the Establishment of a Rice Engineering Centre,", 1966 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - India & Japan trips: correspondence, itineraries, & related materials, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Institute of International Education trip to India: correspondence, notes, travel plans, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Information on passports, visas, & medical records, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - ASAE Special Crops Processing Committee, EPP-49, 1967-1983 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - ASAE Special Crops Processing Committee, Standards, 1977-1982 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Curing with Ethylene, 1976-1980 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - North Carolina Department of Agriculture, Fred Scott correspondence, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Trip to Yugoslavia, 1982-1983 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Trip to Spain, 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Conferences & Meetings, to 1970, 1963-1970 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Conferences & Meetings, 1971-1974 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Conferences & Meetings, 1975-1978 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Trip to Rhodesia, 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - 5th International Tobacco Congress Papers, Section 4, Theme 1, 1969-1970 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Report on Project 5-288, "Systems Engineering of the Cultural & Processing Operations in Tobacco," to RJ Reynolds Tobacco Co., 1964 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Report on Project 5-288, "Systems Engineering of the Cultural & Processing Operations in Tobacco," to RJ Reynolds Tobacco Co., 1965 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Report copies, 1962-1975 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Report copies, 1976-1984 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Flue-Cured Tobacco Marketing Information, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Harvesting & Curing handwritten outline, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - WHJ Report - Research Proposal on Natural & Mechanical Drying of Paddy, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Letter to Dr. D.M. Gopinath, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Oversize documents for trip to India with assignment at Kharagpur, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Letter and reference list from A.C. Pandya to W.H. Johnson, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - ASAE Special Crops Processing Committee, EPP-49, University of Tennessee Memorandum, 1975 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Curing with Ethylene article, 1976 (Box 46, Folder 18)
- Tobacco Freeze-Drying Research Correspondence, 1967-1983; 0 linear feet
  The William H. Johnson Tobacco Freeze-Drying Research Correspondence series documents Johnson's correspondence with companies such as Philip Morris, Monsanto, E.I. Dupont, Liggett & Myers, and R.J. Reynolds.
  - Correspondence related to freeze-dry process, 1969-1976 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence related to freeze-dry process, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Close-grown tobacco correspondence with Hugh Hardison of Export Leaf Tobacco Company, 1976-1978 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - General Cigar Company correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - FMC Corporation Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - E. I. Dupont, 1968-1973 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Monsanto, 1976-1980 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - John Tate - Lipton Tea, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Peter J. Schweitzer Co., 1976-1979 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Theodorus Neimeyer, LTD, Holland, 1969-1971 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Universal Leaf Tobacco Co., 1969-1977 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - National Cotton Council, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Tiedemanns Tobaksfabrik, Norway, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Rothmans of Pall Mall, Ltd., Australia, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - H. F. & Ph.F. Reemtsma, Hamburg, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Swedish Tobacco Co. (Svenska Tobaks Aktiebolaget), 1969-1979 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - AMF, Inc., 1971-1978 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Martin Brinkmann Ag Bremen, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - D.E.J. International Research Co., N.V., Holland, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Leybold, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - List of inquiries or interests, re: freeze-drying process, 1970-1972 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Tobacco Experiment, Weybrew, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - William Firth, Rembrandt Co. Fields Leaf Tobacco Co., 1969 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Alfred N. Hertz, Hamburg, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Tenco, Division of Coca-Cola, 1972-1973 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Freeze-Drying Research Samples, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Imperial Tobacco Co., 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Stokes Plastics & Vacuum Equipment, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Tennessee Eastman Co., 1969-1970 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - International Flavors & Fragrances, Inc. (IFF), 1974 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Pabrik Tembakau "Djarum," Indonesia, Bambang Hartano, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - American Tobacco Co., American Brands, 1958-1971 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - RJ Reynolds Report, 1972-1976 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Imperial Tobacco Co., Ltd, 1977 letter & associated materials, 1972-1977 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Imperial Tobacco Co., Ltd, close-grown tobacco & cut strip, 1973-1978 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Cooperative work with John Campbell of Imperial Tobacco on cut-strip & close-grown tobacco, 1975-1982 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Carreras Rothmans Ltd., Folder 1, 1975-1983 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Carreras Rothmans Ltd., Folder 2, 1969-1978 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - 1974 Report to Carreras Rothmans (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 1975 Report to Carreras Rothmans (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - 1976 Report to Carreras Rothmans (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - 1977 Report to Carreras Rothmans (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - 1978 Report to Carreras Rothmans (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - 1979 Report to Carreras Rothmans (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Florida Times-Union article, "Tobacco experiments showing promise for future,", 1978 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - "Griffin Farm Trials 1976" and "Present Position on Flue-Cured Tobacco, with Stalk, for Sheet Manufacture,", 1974-1976 and undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Basil Akehurst (Carreras Rothmans Ltd.), handwritten note, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Tobacco sample analysis papers (Carreras Rothmans Ltd.), 1971 & undated (Box 46, Folder 17)
- Sketches and Drawings, 1967-1983; 0 linear feet
  The William H. Johnson Sketches and Drawings series contains sketches, drawings, and notes documenting Johnson's models for curing units and other tobacco-related apparatuses. This series contains approximately 500 drawings, ranging in size from 8.5" x 11" to 27" x 36", with the majority being 17" x 22".
  - Details - Compartmental Curing Units, Oxford Tobacco Research Station, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Drying Unit - High Temp - Conceptual model for rapid-drying of yellowed tobacco leaf, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Mini-barns, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Fabrication details, basket for layer-curing research, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Untitled drawings, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Basket for layer-curing research, drawings, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Tobacco Shredder - components, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Untitled drawings, II, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Drawings, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Drawings, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Drawings, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Drawings, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Drawings, 1978-1979 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Drawings, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Drawings, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Drawings, (1 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Drawings, (2 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Drawings, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Drawings, 1972-1973 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Drawings, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Drawings, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Drawings, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Drawings, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Drawings, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Drawings, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Side Draft Curing Barn, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Side Draft Curing Module, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Mini-barns, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Oversize handwritten notes & sketches, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Export Leaf Tobacco Co. memo, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Diagrams and sketches for structural components, 1972-1974 (Flatfolder 1)
  - Drawings and diagrams of agricultural machinery and structural components, 1956-1975 (Flatfolder 2)
  - Drawings and diagrams of tobacco processing related items, 1967-1975 (Flatfolder 3)
  - Tobacco research and processing-related materials, 1958-1977 (Flatfolder 4)
  - Drawings and diagrams of agricultural machinery and structural components, 1968-1983 (Flatfolder 5)
  - Agricultural engineering assorted drawings and documents, 1969-1981 (Flatfolder 6)
  - Drawings and diagrams of agricultural machinery, structures, and components, 1963-1990 (Flatfolder 7)
  - Diagrams and sketches for agricultural engineering structural components, 1969-1989 (Flatfolder 8)